Guide to the W. Sterling Cole papers M2023
Special Collections and University Archives, Colgate University Libraries
W. Sterling Cole papers
circa 1930-1984
M2023
Special Collections and University Archives, Colgate University Libraries
1.8 Cubic feet
Cole, W. Sterling, (William Sterling), 1904-1987
Access to Collection
Collection is open for research.
International Atomic Energy Agency.; Nuclear energy--Government policy.
- Provisional record of the Two Hundred and Sixty-second meeting of the IAEA, 1961 June 27; 17 pp. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- IAEA Progress Reported to UN General Assembly, 8 pp. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Ninth Annual Conference of the American Assoc. for the UN, 1959 March 9; 11 pp. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- TL to Cole from H. D. Smyth, 1959 October 9; 3 pp. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- TL to Cole from G. W. C. Tait, 1959 August 26; 3 pp. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- TL from Cole to H. D. Smyth, 1959 November 19; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Text of Cole's statement before the General Assembly of UN, 1958 October 30; 6 pp. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Statute of the Int. Atomic Energy Agency, 1957 May 10, 14, 15, and 20; 259 pp. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Conference report on above statute, 1957 January; 28 pp. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- TL to Cole from H. D. Smyth, 1959 December 7; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- TL from Cole to H. D. Smyth, 1959 December 17; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- TL from Cole to Lewis L. Strauss, 1961 October 10; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- TL from Cole to Lewis Strauss, 1959 July 16; 3 pp. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- TL from Cole to Lewis Strauss, 1961 January 23; 4 pp. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- TL from Cole to Lewis Strauss, 1959 June 22; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- TL from Cole to Lewis Strauss, 1958 February 19; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- TL from Cole to Lewis Strauss, 1958 July 30; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- TL to Cole from Francis Wilcox, 1957 November 27; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Second UN Conference on the Peaceful Uses of Atomic Energy, 1958 September 1; 4 pp. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Second session of the General Conference of the IAEA, 1958 September 22; 8 pp. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- TL from Lewis Strauss to Cole, 1958 February 11; 4 pp. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- TL from Cole to Robert Oppenheimer, 1960 April 11; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- TL from Cole to Robert Oppenheimer, 1960 May 2; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- TL to Cole from Francis Wilcox, 1957 November 27; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- TL to Cole from Robert Murphy, 1959 October 13 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- TL to Cole from Robert Murphy, 1959 November 3 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Handbook of Procedures for Processing United States Citizens for employment with international organizations, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- TL from Cole to Robert Murphy, 1959 September 17; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- TL to Cole from Robert Murphy, 1959 September 9; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- TL from Cole to Walter Disney, 1958 October 1; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Summary of decisions, 16 to 20 December, 1958 May 28; 10 pp. (Box 1, Folder 17)
- TL to Cole from Pavel Winkler, 1957 December 20; 3 pp. (Box 1, Folder 18)
- TL from Cole to Harold Vedeler, 1958 February 22; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 18)
- TL from Cole to Robert McKinney, 1958 June 19; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 18)
- TL from Cole to Paul Foster, 1960 June 20; 3 pp. (Box 1, Folder 19)
- TL from Cole to Paul Foster, 1960 August 23; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 19)
- TL to Cole from Paul Foster, 1960 August 26 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- General statement by the US. On IAEA Program and Budget, 1958 June 17; 8 pp. (Box 1, Folder 20)
- TL to Cole from Paul Foster, 1960 February 3; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 21)
- TL to Cole from John McCone, 1959 September 25 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- TL from Cole to John McCone, 1959 August 29 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- TL from Cole to John Graham, 1961 March 9; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 22)
- TL from Cole to Glenn Seaborg, 1961 March 9; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 22)
- TL from Cole to Secretary of State, 1961 March 9; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 22)
- TL from Cole to Bourke Hickenlooper, 1961 March 6; 3 pp. (Box 1, Folder 23)
- TL from Cole to Bourke Hickenlooper, 1961 March 8; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 23)
- TL to Cole from Chet Holifield, 1961 March 15; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 23)
- TL from Cole to Harry Brynielsson, 1958 January 8; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 24)
- TL from Cole to Harry Brynielsson, 1960 May 11; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 24)
- TL to Cole from Brynielsson, 1961 February 14; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 24)
- TL to Cole from Brynielsson, 1960 May 19; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 25)
- TL from Cole to Brynielsson, 1961 January 26; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 25)
- TL from Cole to Lewis Strauss, 1958 July 18; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 25)
- TL from Cole to Lewis Strauss, 1958 May 12; 3 pp. (Box 1, Folder 26)
- TL from Cole to Lewis Strauss, 1959 July 23; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 26)
- TL from Cole to Lewis Strauss, 1959 September 25; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 26)
- TL from Cole to Christian A. Herter, 1959 January 21; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 27)
- TL from Cole to Mr. Wilton B. Persons, 19 60 August 23; 3 pp. (Box 1, Folder 27)
- TL from Cole to Sam Rayburn, 1957 October 21; 3 pp. (Box 1, Folder 27)
- TL from Cole to Alfred Iddles, 1958 July 23; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 28)
- TL to Cole from Joseph Martin, 1957 August 29; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 28)
- TL from Cole to Joseph Martin, 1957 August 26 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Conference on the Statute of the IAEA, 1956 November 27; 82 pp. (Box 1, Folder 29)
- The IAEA, 1957 March; 11 pp. (Box 1, Folder 30)
- TL from Cole to James Wadsworth, 1957 August 29; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 31)
- TL to Cole from John Foster Dulles, 1957 September 5; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Memo from UUNA-A. W. Ford, 1957 September 6; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 32)
- TL to Cole from James Wadsworth, 1957 September 3; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 32)
- TL to Cole from James Wadsworth, 1957 August 22; 3 pp. (Box 1, Folder 33)
- TL to Cole from Randolph Burgess, 1957 July 11; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 33)
- TL to Paul f. Foster from W. F. Libby, 1959 December 15; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Statement of Sterling Cole, Chairman, JCAE, 1953 December 8; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Statement of Sterling Cole before Senate Comm. on Foreign Relations, undated; 17 pp. (Box 1, Folder 35)
- State Dept. cablegrams, 1960 August 28; 2 cablegrams (Box 1, Folder 36)
- State Dept. cablegrams, 1960 September 22 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- TL to Cole from J. H. Atkinson, 1956 April 11; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 37)
- TL to Cole from Mamoru Sueda, 1961 April 4 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- TL from Cole to Sueda, 1961 October 20 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- TL from Cole to Tom A. Jenkins, 1957 September 4; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 38)
- TL to Cole from William Colmer, 1957 September 6; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 38)
- TL from Cole to Colmer, 1957 September 4; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 38)
- The Future of Hydrogen Weapons, 1957 February 15; 4 pp. (Box 1, Folder 39)
- TL to Cole from J. H. Atkinson, 1955 December 22; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 40)
- TL from Cole to J. Edgar Hoover, 1957 December 21 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- TL to Cole from Hoover, 1957 October 10; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 40)
- TNS from Dwight David Eisenhower to Sterling Cole, Gettysburg, Pennsylvania, 1961 October 31 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  Note has been removed and housed in M4002, Presidential letters collection, Box 2 Folder 29.
- TL to Cole from Carl A. Kallgren, 1957 December 3; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 42)
- TL from Cole to Kallgren, 1958 February 10; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 42)
- TL to Cole from John Foster Dulles, 1957 September 5; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 42)
- TL to Cole from Mamoru Sueda, 1961 November 20; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 43)
- TL to Cole from Ralph Bunche, 1957 November 1; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 43)
- TL from Cole to Bunche, 1957 November 5; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Financial Protection Against Atomic Hazards, 1957 January; 65 pp. (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Statement before Economic and Social Council, 1958 July 10; 7 pp. (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Draft materials from Second Geneva Conference. [i.e. drafts of the same article], undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
- TL from Cole to Leslie Arends, 1957 September 4 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- TL from Cole to Gordon Ridenour, 1957 September 4; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 47)
- TL from Cole to Edward Herbert, 1957 September 4; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 47)
- TL to Cole from Helen Pittsley, 1957 August 25; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 48)
- TL to Cole from Pittsley, 1957 August 27; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 48)
- TL from Cole to Pittsley, 1957 September 4 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- TL from Cole to Edith Rogers, 1957 September 4; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 49)
- TL from Cole to William Hess, 1957 September 4; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 49)
- TL from Cole to William H. Hill, 1957 September 4; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 49)
- TL from Cole to Francis Norm, 1957 August 20; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 50)
- TL from Cole to Myron Albrio, 1957 August 20; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 50)
- TL to Cole from Dana Near and Bob Bolger, 1957 August 31; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 50)
- TL to Cole from John Foster Dulles, 1957 September 5; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 51)
- TL from Cole to Gerard Smith, 1957 September 13; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 51)
- TL to Cole from Sam Rayburn, 1957 August 21; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 51)
- The Forum Memo, 1957 March (Box 1, Folder 52)
- TL to Cole from Mowry Skinkle, 1957 August 24; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 53)
- TL from Cole to John Griffith, 1957 November 22; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 53)
- TL to Cole from Griffith, undated; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 53)
- TL to Cole from Robert Ginna, 1957 November 18; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 54)
- TL to Cole from William Mitchell, 1957 November 18; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 54)
- TL to Cole from Francis Dorn, 1957 November 15; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 54)
- TL to Cole from Mildred O'Brien, 1957 November 11; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 55)
- TL from Cole to O'Brien, 1957 November 21; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 55)
- TL to Cole from Ralph Bunche, 1957 November 6; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Cole speech to Lockheed Management, 1957 November 12; 9 pp. (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Limiting Nuclear Test Explosions (the Opposition Case), undated; 10 pp. (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Cole speech to graduating class of Int. School of Nuclear Science and Engineering, Argonne National Laboratory, 1957 November 6; 7 pp. (Box 1, Folder 58)
- TL from Cole to Clair Burdick, 1957 November 22; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 59)
- TL to Cole from Paul Davidson, 1957 November 19; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 59)
- TL to Cole from R. H. Austin, 1957 October 22; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 59)
- Employment opportunities in the IAEA, 1957 August; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 60)
- To Cole from "Mary", undated; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 61)
- TL to Cole from Walter Phair, 1957 October 21 (Box 1, Folder 61)
- TL from Cole to Paul Jolles, 1957 October 25; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 61)
- TL to Cole from George Gleason, 1957 October 17; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 62)
- TL from Cole to Gleason, 1957 October 22; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 62)
- TL to Cole from J. A. Robertson, 1957 November 20; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 62)
- TL to Cole from Charles Weaver, 1957 November 8; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 63)
- TL from Cole to Weaver, 1957 November 25 (Box 1, Folder 63)
- TL to Hotel Bristol (Box 1, Folder 64)
- TL to Hotel Kummer from Mary Papworth (Box 1, Folder 64)
- TLS to Cole from Dr. Albert N. Tarulis (Box 1, Folder 64)
- Address by the Director General, Mr. Sterling Cole, to the Second Session of the General Conference of the International Atomic Energy Agency, 1958 September 22; 7 pp. (Box 1, Folder 65)
- Statement of Directory General at the Opening Session of the Second Regular Session of the General Conference at the Hofburg, 1958 September 22; 10 pp. (Box 1, Folder 66)
- General Conference Delegations, 1958 October 3-4; 29 pp. (Box 2, Folder 67)
- Second General Conference, Notes for the Director General, Vienna, Neve Hofburg, 1958 September 22; 4 pp. (Box 2, Folder 68)
- Some Words for NY Speech, Presentation Report to UN General Assembly, UN Headquarters, 1958 October 30; 4 pp. (Box 2, Folder 69)
- Presentation Report to UN General Assembly, UN Headquarters, 1958 October 30; 8 pp. (Box 2, Folder 70)
- "IAEA After its First Year of Work," manuscript written for Nuclear Power, 1959 January; 6 pp. (Box 2, Folder 71)
- For Mr. Clark of "Time and Life", 1959 January 18; 2 pp. (Box 2, Folder 72)
- Remarks by Sterling Cole, Director General of the IAEA, at the Opening Symposium on Medical Isotope Scanning, at the Hofburg, Vienna, 1959 February 25 (Box 2, Folder 73)
- Bulletin to the Schools, Vol. 45, no. 7, The University of the State of New York, 1959 March (Box 2, Folder 74)
  Includes brief biography of Cole on pg. 264.
- Remarks of Sterling Cole, Director General, International Atomic Energy Agency, before the Ninth Annual Conference of the American Association for the United Nations, Hotel Statler, Washington, D.C., 1959 March 9; 11 pp. (final draft) and 23 pp. (rough draft) (Box 2, Folder 75)
- Cole article for the Bulletin of Atomic Scientists, 1959 April; 10 pp. (Box 2, Folder 76)
- Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists, Vol. XV, no. 4, 1959 April 1 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  See pages 160-163 for Cole article.
- Cooperation or Confusion, article for "Trusts and Estates", 1959 April; 8 pp. (Box 2, Folder 77)
- Speech at Seminar on Training of Specialists in the Peaceful Uses of Atomic Energy, Saclay, France, 1959 June 24; 3 pp. (Box 2, Folder 78)
- Opening Statement by IAEA Director General Sterling Cole at Press Conference in Warsaw, 1959 September 7; 3 pp. (Box 2, Folder 79)
- Director General's Opening Address, Warsaw Conference, 1959 September 7; 3 pp. (Box 2, Folder 80)
- La Propriété Industrielle Nucléaire, no. 19, 1959; (2 copies) (Box 2, Folder 81)
  See letter from Cole on pg. 5. Letter in English, remainder of publication in French.
- Lettre de Monsieur le Directur Général de l'Agencie Internationale de l'Energie Atomique, 1959 August 24; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 82)
- Mr. Cole's Statement to the Press on Arrival in Tokyo, Third Japan Conference on Radioisotopes, 1959 September 14-16; 2 pp. (Box 2, Folder 83)
- General Conference Delegations and Committees, 1959 September 22-1959 October 2 (Box 2, Folder 84)
- Address of Director General, Third Session, General Conference, International Atomic Energy Agency, 1959 September 22; 19 pp. (2 copies) (Box 2, Folder 85)
- ITV London, 1959 October 2; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 86)
- TL to Lewis L. Strauss, 1961 August 8; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 87)
- TLS to Cole from Strauss, 1961 July 28; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 87)
- ALS to Cole and Betty from Alice Strauss, no year March 9; 2 pp. (Box 2, Folder 87)
- AL to Cole from Lewis Strauss, 1961 July 28; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 88)
- TL to Cole from Edward Farley, 1957 November 12; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 89)
- TL from Cole to Farley, 1957 November 21; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 89)
- TL from Cole to Lewis Strauss, 1961 October 24 (Box 2, Folder 89)
- TL from Cole to Lewis Strauss, 1960 January 19; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 90)
- TL to Cole from Strauss, 1960 April 28; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 90)
- TL from Cole to Strauss, 1960 May 31; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 90)
- TL from Lewis Strauss to W. J. DuBose (re. Cole), 1960 January 12; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 91)
- TL to Cole from Strauss, 1960 January 6; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 91)
- TL to Strauss from W. J. DuBose (re. Cole), 1960 January 19; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 91)
- TL to Cole from Strauss, 1959 May 2; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 92)
- TL to Cole from Strauss, 1959 May 5; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 92)
- TL to Cole from Strauss, 1959 June 12; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 92)
- TL from Cole to Strauss, 1959 August 27; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 93)
- TL to Cole from Mary Whitley, 1959 May 11; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 93)
- TL to Cole from "Corbin", 1959 May 9; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 93)
- TL to Cole from Strauss, 1958 August 15; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 94)
- TL to Cole from Strauss, 1958 December 23; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 94)
- TL from Cole to Strauss, 1959 May 5; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 94)
- TL to Cole from Strauss, 1958 July 31; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 95)
- TL to Cole from Strauss, 1958 July 31; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 95)
- TL from Cole to Strauss, 1958 August 6; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 95)
- TL from Cole to Strauss, 1958 June 30; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 96)
- TL to Cole from Strauss, 1958 July 11; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 96)
- TL from Cole to Strauss, 1958 July 17; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 96)
- TL from Cole to Strauss, 1958 May 29; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 97)
- TL from Cole to Strauss, 1958 June 23; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 97)
- TL to Cole from Strauss, 1958 June 23; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 97)
- TL from Cole to Strauss, 1958 April 24; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 98)
- TL to Cole from Strauss, 1958 April 28; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 98)
- TL to Cole from Strauss, 1958 May 23; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 98)
- TL to Cole from Strauss, 1858 February 25; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 99)
- TL from Cole to Strauss, 1958 March 4; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 99)
- TL from Cole to Strauss, 1958 April 18; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 99)
- Memorandum from Bryan LaPlante to Commissioners IAEA, 1958 February 20; 2 pp. (Box 2, Folder 100)
- TL to Cole from Strauss, undated; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 101)
- TL to Cole from Strauss, 1958 February 3; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 101)
- TL to Cole from Strauss, 1958 May 6; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 101)
- Lewis Strauss. Press release, 1958 May 3; 3 pp. (Box 2, Folder 102)
- Text of Meet the Press, 1958 April 27; 24 pp. (Box 2, Folder 103)
- TL from Cole to Strauss, 1957 December 9; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 104)
- TL from Cole to Strauss, 1958 February 25; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 104)
- TL from Cole to Mrs. Harold Vance, 1959 September 4; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 105)
- TL to Cole from Harold Vedeler, 1959 October 14; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 105)
- TL to Cole from Paul Sozanz, 1961 April 15; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 105)
- AN from Cole to Mrs. Emlie Zoller, 1960 June 3 (Box 2, Folder 106)
- TL to Cole from Domenick Gabrielli, 1959 March 31; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 107)
- TL from Cole to Gabrielli, 1959 April 6; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 107)
- TL from Cole to Herbert Vetter, 1958 September 27; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 107)
- Minutes of Vienna Church Board meetings, 1961 February 13, April 10, May 8 (Box 2, Folder 108)
- TL to Cole from Vienna Community Church, 1961 January 14; 3 pp. (Box 2, Folder 109)
- TL to Cole from Vienna Community Church, 1961 June 1; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 109)
- TL to Cole from Kenneth Ziebell, 1961 January 30; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 109)
- Vienna Community Church order of worship, 1960 December 4 (Box 2, Folder 110)
- Vienna Community Church board meeting minutes, 1960 December 13 (Box 2, Folder 110)
- Vienna Community Church board meeting minutes, 1961 January 9 (Box 2, Folder 110)
- Vienna Community Church documents, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 111)
- Vienna Community Church documents, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 112)
- Vienna Community Church documents, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 113)
- Summary of American candidacy situation, undated; 4 pp. (Box 2, Folder 114)
- AL to Cole from Alice Wynd, 1957 November 19; 2 pp. (Box 2, Folder 115)
- TL from Cole to Wynd, 1957 November 22; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 115)
- "Is This the Way to Start?" Izvestiia, 1957 October 10 (Box 2, Folder 116)
- Eisenhower speech, 1954 March; 3 pp. (Box 2, Folder 117)
- The Statute of the IAEA, 1957 March 21; 42 pp. (Box 2, Folder 118)
- UN Atoms for Peace, 1956 October 25 (Box 2, Folder 119)
- TL to Cole from George Norris, Jr., 1957 October 25; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 120)
- TL to Cole from Jay LeFevre, 1957 November 12; 2 pp. (Box 2, Folder 120)
- TL to Cole from Quentin Matt, 1957 November 7; 2 pp. (Box 2, Folder 120)
- Agreement between US and Austria, 1957 January 17; 13 pp. (Box 2, Folder 121)
- The 1957 Nuclear Industry Problems and Progress, 1957 October 28-31; 16 pp. (Box 2, Folder 122)
- 3 TLs from Cole to Paul Jolles, 1957 November 14 (Box 2, Folder 123)
- TL from Cole to George M. Kennan, 1957 October 11; 2 pp. (Box 2, Folder 124)
- TL from Cole to George Kennan, 1957 October 30; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 124)
- Vienna Community Church materials (Box 2, Folder 125)
- Vienna Community Church [hereafter VCC] materials (Box 2, Folder 126)
- VCC materials (Box 2, Folder 127)
- VCC materials (Box 2, Folder 128)
- VCC materials (Box 2, Folder 129)
- VCC materials (Box 2, Folder 130)
- VCC materials (Box 2, Folder 131)
- VCC materials (Box 2, Folder 132)
- VCC materials (Box 2, Folder 133)
- VCC materials (Box 2, Folder 134)
- VCC materials (Box 2, Folder 135)
- VCC materials (Box 2, Folder 136)
- VCC materials (Box 2, Folder 137)
- VCC materials (Box 2, Folder 138)
- TL Vinson to Cole, 1960 March 3; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 139)
- TL Vinson to Cole, 1958 December 8; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 139)
- TL Cole to Vinson, 1958 November 24; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 139)
- TL Cole to Vinson, 1958 January 15; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 139)
- TL Wadsworth to Cole, 1960 March 23; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 140)
- TL Cole to Wadsworth, 1960 May 19; 1 p (Box 3, Folder 140)
- TL Walker to Cole, 1958 October 29; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 140)
- TL Clark to Vogel, 1960 March 9; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 141)
- TL Vogel to Cole, 1960 February 24; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 141)
- TL Vogel to Cole, 1959 November 18; 1 p (Box 3, Folder 141)
- TL Vogel to Clark, 1959 November 10; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 141)
- TL Vogel to Cole, 1959 October 9; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 141)
- TL Cole to von Mayer-Gunthof, 1959 February 11; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 142)
- Art Treasures in Austria Card (Box 3, Folder 142)
- Voice of America in Europe Card. (Box 3, Folder 142)
- TL Cole to von Mautner Markof, 1959 January 23; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 143)
- TL von Mehren to Cole, 1960 June 29; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 143)
- TL von Mehren to Cole, 1960 June 29; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 143)
- Francis T.P. Plimpton's Business card with note, 1960 July 11 (Box 3, Folder 144)
- TL Cole to F. Ward, 1960 January 7; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 144)
- Cole to Warren, 1958 October 22; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 144)
- TL Rusk to Cole, 1961 February 21; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 145)
- TL Cole to Rusk, 1961 February 10; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 145)
- TL Cole to Herter, 1960 December 10; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 145)
- TL Wainhouse to Cole, 1960 December 1; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 145)
- TL Cole to Herter, 1960 November 29; 2 pp. (Box 3, Folder 146)
- TL Donahue to Cole, 1958 September 10; 2 pp. (Box 3, Folder 146)
- TL Cole to Watson, 1959 January 8; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 146)
- TL Watson to Cole, 1958 December 31; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 146)
- TL Ward to Cole, 1958 March 5; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 147)
- TL Cole to Ward, 1958 February 26; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 147)
- TL Cole to Ward, 1958 February 26; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 147)
- TL Ward to Cole, 1958 March 5; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 147)
- TL Cole to Wattles, 1961 February 28; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 148)
- TL Cole to Wattles (with card), 1959 January 8; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 148)
- TL Cole to Weatherby, 1958 June 13; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 148)
- TL Weatherby to Cole, 1958 June 5; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 148)
- TL Alexandrides to Cole, 1957 February 27; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 149)
- TL Payne to Cole, 1957 November 22; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 149)
- TL Cole to Bell, 1958 February 6; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 149)
- TL Bell to Cole, 1957 December 19; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 149)
- TL Cole to Hughes, 1958 February 6; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 150)
- TL Hughes to Cole, 1957 December 17; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 150)
- TL Cole to Jacobs, 1958 February 6; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 150)
- TL Jacobs to Cole, 1957 December 4; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 150)
- TL Shaults to Cole, 1957 December 13; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 151)
- TL Cole to Shaw, 1958 February 6; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 151)
- TL Shaw to Cole, 1958 January 9; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 151)
- TL Cole to Becker, 1958 February 10; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 152)
- TL Becker to Cole, 1958 January 9; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 152)
- TL Cole to Bergin, 1958 February 10; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 152)
- TL Bergin to Cole, 1957 November 29; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 152)
- TL Cole to Wharton, 1958 February 10; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 153)
- TL Wharton to Cole, 1957 November 25; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 153)
- TL Cole to Philbin, 1958 January 17; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 153)
- TL Philbin to Cole, 1958 January 9; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 153)
- TL Cole to Cavicchia, 1958 January 16; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 154)
- TL Cavicchia to Cole, 1957 December 8; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 154)
- TL Cole to Keenan, 1958 January 17; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 154)
- Keenan to Cole, 1958 January 8; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 154)